# Bjørn Tore Svinningen

Heliveien 945, 1820 Spydeberg, Norway

Phone: +47 90516604

Mail: postmannen@gmail.com | twitter: twitter.com/erter1 | github: github.com/postmannen

### **Summary**

A creative technophile with a great passion for learning new things. My interests ranging from Programming, IT, Psychology, Economy, Art, Guitar, Piano, Electronics, Hydraulics, Farming..and more.

In 2017 I decided to add Go Development to that list.

My broad experience often helps me see problem scenarios and new solutions as a whole. This have made me build good products with the customer in mind, and helped solving complex problems within project and team work.

I first started programming in Pascal about 3 decades ago, but things happened and my main work became networks and servers, where programming was something I continued to do, but occasionally. In 2017 I decided to switch that around, and do development as the main thing.

### **Professional Experience**

Been working with Data centers, Network, Security, Servers, and Monitoring since 1997, and made the switch to fulltime Development in 2017.

Building Edge Cloud solutions from the ground and up.

The most recent jobs can be found below.

A full list can be found at my LinkedIn profile.

#### 2017 - Present, Go Development

I love to solve problems and challenges.

Some examples are mentioned below:

- Inventor and Creator of the Event Driven infrastructure controller Steward for RaaLabs that
  makes it possible to have full control over your infrastructure both in the cloud as well as on the
  ships sailing the sea.
- Decoding protocols, and write software to control Drones and IOT.
- Network/Server management tools.
- All my projects are available at github.com/postmannen.
- Most of my work are opensourced so what I've been doing can be found in the Contribution Activity on my Github profile.

#### Jan 2020 - Jun 2023 Raa Labs, Contract

Building Cloud on the Edge:

 Build an Edge Cloud infrastructure/platform from the ground and up for ships sailing around the globe.

#### 2004 - Present, Self Employee, Freelance

- · Go / Golang Development.
- Automation and orchestration.
- Network and server monitoring.
- · Network lan / wan & security.
- Linux systems.
- IOT

#### 2013 - 2017, Datametrix AS, Senior Network Consultant

- Network/Security architecture done with Cisco, Checkpoint and F5 on Datametrix's Cloud provider network.
- · Network and services monitoring based on Centreon/Nagios.
- Automation and orchestration of cloud services
- Scripting/Programming in Perl and JavaScript.
- Design and implementation of Monitoring platform counting 40k+ monitored services.

#### 2012 - 2013, IPsoft, Senior Network Consultant

- Senior Network Consultant.
- Technical Project Lead.
- Monitoring and Automation.

### 2008 - 2012, Steria AS, Senior Network Consultant

- Network Design, implementation and management.
- Implementation projects of large and smaller customers: Planning, migration, customer relationship.
- Maintenance of Steria's datacenter's based on Cisco hardware.
- · Network monitoring based on Centreon/Nagios.

#### 2004 - 2008, Nortura, Senior Network Consultant

- Responsible for Lan/Wan, Security.
- Maintainance and implementation of Linux and Windows servers.
- System monitoring based on Centreon/Nagios and other monitoring tools available on the Linux platform.

#### 2004 - 2004, Systeam, System Consultant

Maintainance of customer network, servers and computers.

#### 1997 - 2003, Telenor Mobil, System Consultant

- Network and server maintenance.
- Customer support.

## **Technical Experience**

I like to know how solutions, technology and the value chain work as a whole. Other areas where i have good experience are:

- Operating systems with services: Linux and Windows.
- Monitoring systems.
- Logging systems.

#### Industries and verticals

- IT Data Center, Service Provider and Cloud.
- Telecom.
- Farming and food production.
- Shipping.

#### My Side Project

Use Drones, IOT, and Code to get better control and results in agriculture.

#### **Open Source**

• All my code and learning material are put available on Github. Hopefully for others to use, learn from, or for detecting issues in the code I have yet to know of.

#### Some more examples below

- Async management of servers/endpoints using Nats where everything is done with passing messages and concurrent. Steward
- Traffic sniffer who lets you know what your computer communicated with, and how much data transfered. trafficmonitor
- Driver for Parrot drones. parrot

#### Things I plan to look more into in the future

- Use of Go with embedded devices and micro controllers.
- Read and analyze Network Data with Go.

### **Education**

### 1991-1995, Electronics, Certificate Of Apprenticeship

 1991-1995 Electronics, Computer Technical/Hardware, Micro controllers, Pascal, ASM, Audio/Video.

### Languages

- Norwegian (native speaker)
- English